Guide to the Situationist Collection, 1957-2005.
Situationist Collection
- Publications
  - Exhibit Catalogs
    - I denne transistarsommer eller dagen H, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      Jörgen Nash; Bauhaus Situationniste; includes copy of letter from Jorgen Nash
    - La Luxure de L'esthesie, December 1970 - January 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      Asger Jorn
    - La Société du Spectacle Program, October 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Program from premiere screening of Guy Debord film
    - Museum der Moderne Salzburg Exhibition Preview, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Preview of Les Grands Spectacles: 120 Years of Art and Mass Culture, Plays of Light, Gerhard Richter: Printed!, Mimmo Paladino: Sculpture & Painting; 2 copies
    - Polesien Breder Sig af Lars Morell, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Jorgen Nash, Drakabygget & Situationisterne
    - Popvecka, November 22-27, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      manuscript notes on the cover by Jacqueline de Jong
    - Seven Rebels, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
      1st edition with Jacqueline de Jong's entry intaact (last date noted: 1962)
    - Situationister: 1957-1971 Drakabygget, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Lund: Skanska Konstmuseum
    - Tajiri, April - June 1967 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      Stedelijk Museum
    - Translations, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      Monograph of Asger Jorn's "Vision-Colour" Exhibition July-October 1963
    - Trois Scandinaves, October - November 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      Bauhaus Situationiste; Galerie Delta
  - Photocopies and Articles
    - Photocopies of Publications
      - An Afternoon at the Tate & Lyle, June 16, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - A Brief Introduction to the Critique of Art History and Other Subjects, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        London
      - Brandt for Beginners, June 18, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        London; Part One
      - Chaos In Cancerland, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        Jamie Reid
      - A Critical Review of Decomposition in Britain in 1986, March 24, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        London: The Horse's Mouth
      - Enough is Enough You Fuckers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - A Factory Quartet, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - How Is Your Stiff Neck Today?, June 28, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        Written by the Friends of Renè Magritte
      - Interminable Drivel From Multiple Orifices, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - List For Jamie Reid Exhibition; letter from Arthur McDonald to Jamie Reid; list of questions for Jamie Reid, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
        Assorted Images Limited (Ai)
      - Mass Media, April 1972 (Box 3, Folder 35)
        Mike Bradley & Paul Sieveking
      - Point Blank, Undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
        Includes Do You Ever Feel Like Killing Your Boss?; Do You Ever Feel Like Stealing Everything?; Is There Life Before Death?
      - "Practice of Theory," "The Use of Fourier" by Raoul Vaneigem, Untitled by Paul Sieveking, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - The Return of the Repressed, June 13, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Royal Family & The Poor: Conceptual Art S.I.: A Past Without a Future?, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - SMIRK: THE ARTY LINE, Undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Turning Conflict Into Reality, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Untitled Six Paneled Comic, Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Untitled flyer for film series compiled by Richard Humphreys and Keith Skone; hosted by Tate Gallery, June 1988 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Untitled songs/poems, June 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 44)
        First lines: "somewhere in Africa the sun is shining"; "hierarchical social organisation is like a gigantic racket"; "sexshop, supermarket, synagogue-a-go-go"
    - Articles about Situationist Materials
      - Articles, April 6 - June 27, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        From Hallandsposten, Västgöta-Demokraten, Svenska-Dagbladet, Göteborgs-Posten, Laholms Tidning, Politiken, Expressen, Hallands Nyheter, Göteborgs Handels & Sjöfartstidning, Aftonbladet, Arbetet, Berlinske Aftonavisen
      - Life's a Riot, Undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
        Greil Marcus article; Jack Ben-Levi article
      - New York Post, September 21, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        The Yes Men; Issued a year before print date
      - New York Subway Graffiti & The American Landscape, Bill Meyer, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - The New York Times, July 4, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - "Our Foreign Correspondent Writes", Undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
        Excerpt attributed to Jamie Reid collection
      - Sage Whispers, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 49)
        Article in "Time Out" magazine, November 29-December 5, 1984
      - "The Secret Society of the Spectacle", June 1994 (Box 3, Folder 50)
        Simon Ford; Art Monthly; pg 14-16
      - Situationisterna, pg 23-25, May 1988 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Ephemera
  - Aggression = Death, Undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    Note included says "Richard Alcroft 1986 Vietnam protest"
  - Avantgarde ist Unerwünscht!, January 1961 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Situationistischen Internationale
  - Banksy Stickers - Road Signs, Undated; 9x11.5 in.; 2: 4x4 in.; 2: 4x5 in.; 1: 3.5x4 1/2 in.; 1: 4x6 in. (Box 3, Folder 54)
    BNK/5Y 020, 021,022, 024 (x2), 025, 027; 1:
  - Blood On The Happy Highway, Undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
    Comic, original and photocopy; W. Specer London WC1N 3XX
  - The Compendium "Signs & Things" Catalogue 1982, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    foldout; London: Compendium Bookshop
  - The Compendium "Situations Vacant" Catalogue '82, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - English Tolerance A Mask, Undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - The Ex-school: Experiment Art School 1961-69, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Exhibit invitation; Silkeborg: Museum Jorn
  - Filmsituationistisk Festival Card Advertisement, Undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    Filmfestival Bauhaus Situationniste
  - "It was meant to be great but it's horrible" Confessions: S. Claus 1968, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Jörgen Nash Profile, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    Note in green paint on back; Drakabygget
  - Kampen Om det Situkratiska Samhället: Ett Situationistiskt Manifest, Undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - "Kobra Kabouter", December 13, 1970 - January 31, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    Jacqueline de Jong 1961-71 exhibit advertisement; Onderwijs Kunst Klub
  - Le Gigot, sa Vie et son Oeuvre, Undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    Les Luttes de Classe, Supplement au Numero 2; Strasbourg
  - Letter From Jacqueline de Jong, Paris, February 1967 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - London's Buying Your Crap Flyer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Love is happening: The new little mermaid, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    Leaflet no. 14 from 2 Situationistiske Internationale
  - Minutemen Membership Application Form, Undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Ritus contra Depravation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - The Situationist Times, circa November 15, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    No. 4 International edition; Copenhagen: Rhodos International Videnskabelig Forlag; 2 sizes; date crossed out
  - The Situationist Times Advertisement, November 1964 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    No. 5; Copenhagen: Rhodos, International Science Publishers
  - The Situationist Times Order Form, Undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
    No. 6; Copenhagen: Rhodos, International Science Publishers
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, Undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
    List of Solidarity pamphlets; London; (last date noted: 1973)
  - Three Days To Shock The World Poster, May 17-19, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    International Workshop Bauhaus Situationiste; Drakabygget
  - Tidning För Marginella Poster, Undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Vote for Nobody/Don't Vote Handbill, Undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - "Waarom stemmen lastige Amsterdammers PROVO?", Undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - "Nouveau Théatre D'opérations Dans La Culture", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Internationnale situationniste, Paris
- Artwork
  Mainly arranged by size.
  - Prints and Painting
    - [Epreuve d'Artiste deja] (2 copies), 1962; 8.5x11 in. (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Untitled Print, Undated; 14x11 in. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - ["On Fait Ce Qu'ont Peux"], Jacqueline de Jong; Print, Undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Asger Jorn Print, Undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Jörgen Nash; Original collage; Postcard sized, Undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Jörgen Nash; Original artwork; Filmsituationistisk Festival I Örkel program (1964); Contains inscription from Jörgen Nash to Bo Caverfors, Undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - "Still Life" by Ralf Rumney, 1952; 17 x 13.5 in. (Box 6)
      Framed, oil on board.
  - Broadsides and Posters
    - Art Posters
      - "Pourpuoi Des Professeurs: 2eme edition", March 15, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "Reich: How to Use", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        by Jean-Pierre Voyer of the Institute of Contemporary Prehistory. Translated and published by the Bureau of Public Secrets, Berkeley, California.
      - "Aux Poubelles De L'Histoire", 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Paris, Internationale Situationniste
      - "World Genocide Now", Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "Klagebrew til Radioradet om det Kulturelle Radselsregiments", January 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Flyveblad
      - "Oprab til Danmarks National-Garde Luk Kulture-Ministeriet", October 1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - "Remarks on womens' liberation" (Disalienation Comics no. 1), April 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Original art. Sheffeld, UK. Detourned comic strip.
      - "Mot Ett Jamlikt Samhalle Alla Blir Snutar!", Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Eller Marginella…
      - "Green dialoog met gluiperds = Pas des dialogue avec les suspects", February 27, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Jan Strijbosch and Raoul Vaneigem
      - "Otono 1957: Elecciones Sindicales", 1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Two posters, one signed Laperal, one signed Saez from 1957 union elections in Spain
      - "Bourgeois Vous N'Avez Riencompris", May-June 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Atelier Populaire, Paris
      - "Bevriend Staatshoofd: Hitler, Johnson, Nixon, Soeharto", Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Willemen
      - "I Louis Lingg", Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Printed by Solidarity Publications, Chicago, Illinois
      - "Vote", c. 2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        frieghteningprospect.com
      - "The Blind Men and the Elephant", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Bureau of Public Secrets, Berkeley, California
      - "Imod Politivold", Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - "Internationale Situationniste", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Raoul Vaneigem, detourned comic strip beginning, "Rien manque us confort do l'ennui!"
      - "Impotenta Karlar laser fibban", Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Ochannan Porr
      - "All the Way with L.B.J.", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        William Weege. Happenings Press, Berkeley
      - "When the Heavy Lowering Sky…", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Impeach Johnson", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Napalm", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - PSP Ontwapenend, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Halla!", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Gruppe Spur
      - Januar-Manifest, 1961; 60 x 21.3 cm. (23.6 x 8.4 in.) (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Gruppe Spurl. Bernt Carlson. Bildstormarna
      - Four duplicates from the Happenings press (in folder 4), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - "Reich, Geronimo, Dada: American revolutionaries with a message for England", c. 1968-1969 (Mapcase-folder 1)
        By King Mob
      - "die Situationisten: Alternativ Documenta", 1972 (Mapcase-folder 1)
        Poster by Nash, Zwick, and Strid
      - "Deux Films de Guy Debord: La Société du Spectacle…", c. 1975 (Mapcase-folder 1)
        Poster for a screening of Debord's films
      - Nigeria Non A La Balkanisation…, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
      - "den voldsomme arstid…", December 1967 (Mapcase-folder 2)
      - "Goodbye California", Undated (Mapcase-folder 2)
      - "Seule La Lutte Paye!", Undated (Mapcase-folder 2)
    - Exhibit Posters
      - "An international mail art happening and film art-concept congress exhibition", 1975 (Mapcase-folder 2)
        Broadside invitation to show at the Internationale Akadémie des Beaux Arts Symposium, Ubbedboda, Sweden. Inscribed in manuscript to Bo Cavefors
      - "Festival Draka", Undated (Mapcase-folder 2)
        Situationist Exhibition in Sweden
      - Jörgen Nash, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Poster for an exhibit at Gallerie Hi-Fi, Demark. Inscribed by Nash to Galleri Karlsson
      - "Home to Sweden: Yoshio Nakajima", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Poster for an exhibit at Vernissage, Sweden
      - "Poesiutstallning", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Poster for an Jörgen Nash exhibition Gallerie Heland, Stockholm
      - "Situationister: 1957-1971 Drakabygget", 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Poster for an exhibit at the Skanska Konstmuseum
      - "Zwick: Situationer Konfrontationer", 1976 (Box 5)
        Poster for a Zwick exhibition Gallerie Heland, Stockholm
  - Photographs
    - Philippe Vermés; vintage print of photo used to create the Atelier Populaire poster "Bourgeois Vous N'Avez Rien Compris" signed by Vermés, May 1968 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Constant Nieuwenhuys artwork, Undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
      Handwritten note on back
    - Imaginons la France d'après, Undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Andreotti, Libero & Xavier Costa. Situacionistas: arte, politica, urbanismo, 1996
Andreotti, Libero & Xavier Costa. Theory of the Dérive and other situationist writings on the city, 1996
Anonymous, Stasi Slut, 1992
Astronauts of Inner-Space, 1966
Atkins, Guy. Asger Jorn the crucial years: 1954-1964, 1977
Becker-Ho, Alice & Guy Debord. A Game of War, 2007
Blazwick, Iwona. An endless adventure…an endless passion…an endless banquet: A Situationist Scrapbook, 1989
Brand, Paul. Constant: Opstand van de Homo Ludens, 1969
Brau, Eliane. Le Situationnisme ou la Nouvelle Internationale, 1968
Coeurderoy, Ernest. Pour le Révolution, 1972
Constant: New Babylon
Coverley, Merlin. Psychogeography, 2006
Davidson, Steef. De Kunst Van Het Protest/The Art of the Protest: Posters 1965-1975, 1981
Davidson, Steef. Images de la Revolte: 1965-1975, 1982
Debord, Guy. Comments on the Society of the Spectacle, 2002
Debord, Guy. Considerations on the Assassination of Gerard Lebovici, 2001
Debord, Guy. Correspondence: The Foundation of the Situationist International (June 1957- August 1960), 2009 (2 copies)
Debord, Guy. La Societe do Spectacle, 1967
Debord, Guy. Mémoires, 1993
Debord, Guy. The Society of the Spectacle: The Lisp Translation, 2009
Dejacques, Claude. A Toi L'Angoisse a Moi La Rage, 1968
Elmqvist, Annika & Gittan Jönsson. Annmari Langemar, Pål Rydberg, Historieboken, 1970
Ford, Simon. The Realization and Suppression of the Situationist International: An Annotated Bibliography 1972-1992, 1995
Frankrike 68 Kampen Fortsätter, 1968
Gaillard, Alice. Les Diggers: Révolution et contre-culture à San Francisco (1966-1968), 2014
Gruppe SPUR. Die Zeitschrift SPUR, 1962
Home, Stewart. What Is Situationism? A Reader, 1996
Hussey, Andrew. The Game of War: The Life nad Death of Guy Debord, 2001
Internationale Situationniste 1958-69, (original), 1970
Internationale Situationniste 1958-69, (reprint), 1970
Jorn, Asger. Guldhorn og Lykkehjul, 1957
Jorn, Asger. Jorn a Venezia, 1963
Jorn, Asger. La Flûte de Jade/Jadefløjten/The Jade Flute, 1970
Jorn, Asger. Modifications, 1998
Jorn, Asger. Naturens Orden, 1962
Jorn, Asger. Pour la forme, 2001
Jorn, Asger. Ting Pölis, 1964
Jorn, Asger. Værdi og Økonomi, 1962
Kaufmann, Vincent. Guy Debord, 2003
Knaab, Ken. Public Secrets, 1997
Knaab, Ken. Situationist International Anthology, 1981
Krojer, Tom. Tilliblivelsen, 1977
Lambert, Jean-Clarence. New Babylon Constant: Art et Utopie, 1997
Laumer, March & Hardy Strid. Hardy Strid: The Situationist Superman in Hemol Langauge, 1983
Levy, "Yank" Bert. Guerrilla Warfare, 1964
L'Histoire du Cinema Francais, 1990
Magnus, Carl & Jörgen Nash. Heimrad Prem, Hardy Strid, Jens Jørgen Thorsen, Situationister I Konsten, 1966
McDonough, Tom. The Situationists and the City, 2009
Nash, Jørgen. Hanegal: Gallisk Poesialbum, 1961
Nash, Jørgen. Her er jeg: Samlede Digte 1942-75, 1975
Not Bored!: Anthology 1983-2010, 2011
Nuttall, Jeff. Bomb Culture, 1970
Ohrt, Robert. Phantom Avantgarde:Eine Geschichte der Situationistischen Internationale und der modernen Kunst, 1990
On the Passage of a few people through a rather brief moment in time: The Situationist International 1957-1972, 1989
Peters, Louis F. Kunst en Revolte, 1969
Plant, Sadie. The Most Radical Gesture: The Situationist International in a postmodern age, 1992
Pomerand, Gabriel. Saint Ghetto of the Loans: Grimoire, 2006
Rasmussen, Mikkel Bolt & Jakob Jakobsen. Expect Anything Fear Nothing, 2011
Rosemont, Franklin. Surrealism & Its Popular Accomplices, 1980
Rosendal, Björn The Emotional Intelligence, 1981
Stansill, Peter & David Zane Mairowitz. Bamn (By Any Means Necessary): Outlaw Manifestos and Ephemera 1965-1970, 1971
Thorsen, Jens Jorgen. 1957-70 Situationister, 1971
Vague, Tom. Anarchy in the UK: The Angry Brigade, 1997
Vaneigam, Raoul. Banalita di base, 1969
Vaneigam, Raoul Traité de savoir-vivre à l'usage des jeunes générations, 1967
Vaneigem, Raoul. The Movement of the Free Spirit, 1994
Wark, McKenzie. The Beach beneath the Street, 2011
Woods, Alan. The Map is Not the Territory, 2000
Zweifel, Stefan & Juri Steiner, Heinz Stahlhut. In Girum Imus Nocte et Consumimur Igni - The Situationist International (1957-1972), 1978